I hated myself for so long.
I was ugly and sour
and not charming at all.
"Love brings only terror."
That's what I thought, until...
Akaishi-san.
I really like you.
Will you go out with me?
A massive creature has appeared!
Anyone in the vicinity of the Sumida
River, please evacuate at once!
This is an emergency.
This is an emergency!
We meet again!
Kuro-tan, not again!
Episode 5
A Gyaru and Lipstick
What's going on with you, Kuro-tan?
You've been turning into a kaiju
all the time lately!
Ever since that metal festival!
Will you be all right to start
your new school term like this?
Dry off before you leave the bathroom!
Arata Minami
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
I'll be waiting
in the park.
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
By the big sphere!
Be back later!
I haven't seen him in person
since the festival!
And now I'll get to see him every day!
Akaishi-san!
He's shining even brighter than before!
Good morning.
It's awfully bright today, isn't it?
Maybe I've been playing
too many smartphone games.
Yeah, too many.
Right?
I wish we didn't have to shuffle classes.
Oh, but even if we end up in different
classes, it shouldn't change much.
Since we're...
dating, after all.
Arata!
What brings you here?
Oh, meeting up with my girlfriend.
Huh?
Don't lose it before
the term's even started, man!
Introduce me to her later.
Sure.
That was a close call.
But did he call me his girlfriend?
Introduce me?!
I totally forgot in all the hype.
If people realize
I'm Minami-kun's girlfriend...
No way, Arata! Why Psycho-tan?!
I'm never liking your posts ever again!
He'll be a laughingstock,
and it'll be my fault!
Hey, there you are!
You're fast, Akaishi-san!
D-Don't walk beside me!
Why?
At school, we should pretend
we don't know each other!
If you hang out with me, people will
think something's wrong with you!
You lose friends and likes!
I don't want any likes.
And I don't want friends that shallow.
I can't pretend I don't know you.
You're my girlfriend.
Uh-oh!
Hey, wait!
Akaishi-san, I'm so—
Sorry.
We don't have to pretend
we don't know each other.
But can we pretend
we're just friends instead?
Okay.
I'm sorry to be so selfish.
I wish you'd be more selfish, personally.
Well, I'll walk ahead, then.
Be more selfish?
Do I deserve to do that?
I wish I had more confidence.
Excuse me!
You attend Ginjuji High School, don't you?
Yes...
Could you give this to my brother?
He's a first-year...
No, a second-year now.
His name is Arata Minami.
I know him!
Really?!
He really is popular!
I told him to grab his lunch
and he said he had it!
Now that he's got his new girlfriend,
he can't keep a thought in his head!
There was that whole
kaiju rampage yesterday,
but he didn't even notice
the emergency alarms!
He was all, "Ooh, I was just
thinking about Akaishi-san!"
I suppose this Akaishi-san person
must be very pretty.
Whoops!
Well, take it to him, then!
Minami-kun and Psycho-tan?
That can't really be true.
There he is!
Huh?
He's by himself.
Guess they had it wrong, then.
He'd never go for Psycho-tan!
Don't scare me like that!
Your little sister... wanted me
to bring you your lunch.
And... y-you shouldn't
ignore emergency alarms.
Um... you know. I think...
the kaiju will probably
appear again tonight!
Sure.
I'll be careful.
Class B
Arata Minami
Class C
Kuroe Akaishi
We're separated, huh?
We might be in different classes,
but we can still have lunch together.
R-Right!
See you later!
S-Sure.
Congratulations on your
successful coupling, Kuroe-san!
I'm as happy as if my own love
had borne fruit!
Thanks.
This demands a celebration!
Call Harugon at once!
I was really hoping for
a chill start to the new term.
This is a really bad sign.
I don't want a new class...
I'm more than happy
to be with you, Kuroe-san!
What if some nasty gyaru targets me?
Then I'll protect you
in Minami-kun's place!
Manatsu-san?
Then I can do this!
You're something else, y'know.
How'd you get in with Minami-kun?
Gotta give it up.
I'm deep in the jungle!
Manatsu-san!
Tomosato-san, wanna see
this with me sometime?
I'm afraid I can't follow movies
with only human characters.
Tomosato-san, can I have
your contact info?
She's too popular! I can't see her!
You may not!
You listening to me?
Morning, all!
Hey, lots of people from my last class!
What a great vibe!
Rairi! You look so pretty again!
The orange tones look amazing on you!
Right?!
I saw your cosmetics report yesterday!
Sweet!
Wh-What the...
Her eyes are so wide. Her skin is
so lustrous. The highest caste there is...
If she targets me, I'm doomed.
Rairi, did you hear? That girl over there.
Argh!
They're saying she's
Minami-kun's girlfriend.
I-It begins!
Violence?!
You gotta straighten out that posture.
Hunching over all the time
is really unattractive!
Chest out, chin up!
And look at those lips!
They're all chapped up!
What a waste of great material!
C'mere!
What color should we go with?
Um, Rairi?
Yeah, let's go with this.
We'll use a lip balm scrub
to even them out...
Lip Balm Scrub
Then add some lip concealer...
Lip Concealer
Then we apply the lipstick
just to the center...
Lipstick
Then we blot it outwards with a finger.
Lip Gloss
Then the faintest hint
of gloss to top it off...
All done!
Isn't she the cutest?!
Y-Yeah, it really brings out her color...
What a transformation!
Posi-peace!
P-Posi...?
I'm Kohno Raimu! Call me Rairi, 'kay!
Rairi, do me, too!
Can we get a makeup tutorial?!
I'm on it!
Painting my lips
won't make any difference.
I'm still a kaiju.
But I feel... kinda...
Next up.
Just a little...
I-I'm Akaishi Kuroe.
Feel free to talk to me anytime.
I look forward to studying with you!
Nice to meet you.
Good. Next up.
She seems... kinda nice.
YSM's new lipstick is so vibrant
Wh-What is it?
You seem kinda different
from this morning.
Oh, I thought so, too!
Is it because she's wearing lipstick?
It's like your face is in full flower!
Like the first stage of
a bio-kaiju's evolution!
K-Kaiju?!
I-I'm taking it off.
But it looks wonderful!
It looks great on you! You're beautiful!
Th-Thank you.
Love makes a girl beautiful, as they say.
N-No, a girl from my class did it...
I guess it wiped off while I was eating.
It was such a nice color.
I wonder where she bought it...
I wanna ask...
No, better not.
It looks great on you! You're beautiful!
I totally feel that!
U-Um, Rairi-san?
Where did you buy that lipstick you used?!
She's grossed out. Of course she is.
What's the point of dressing up
a dud like me?
Oh, that?
Wanna come buy some with me?
Are you kidding me? Never thought
I'd go shopping with a gyaru...
What's your first name, by the way?
Kuroe.
Kuro-taso, huh?
"Taso"?
Here we go!
Th-Thank you.
Let's get you some blush to go with it!
P-Please!
What's blush again?
Hey, can I ask you something?
What made you want to look prettier?
Just for ref while we're
picking stuff out.
R-Right... yeah. Um...
Ever since I was a kid, I've been... sick.
It's a visible condition,
and it gave me kind of a complex.
It's made it hard for me
to hang out with people.
And because I couldn't
be honest, Minami-kun—
um, the guy I like...
I gave him all these misunderstandings.
I thought if I had more confidence, maybe
I could be more open with my feelings.
But today, he complimented
the lipstick you gave me.
I suddenly felt lighter than air,
like I could do anything.
I think more shining moments like that
would give me the confidence I need!
S-So... even if I can't be as pretty as
you, I thought I should at least try...
Wh-What did I do?
I'm sorry. You reminded me
of how I used to be.
You'll be okay! I know you can change!
Thank you for coming!
So noisy! Guess they're
doing construction.
That kaiju's been making a lot of
trouble around school too, huh?
I'm sorry.
Hey, wanna hit up a photo booth?
Um, I really don't need
to buy you a new one?
The lipstick you put on me...
Hey, that's no prob!
I've got more than I can hold!
The water line burst!
Rairi-san?
Are you okay?
R-Rairi-san...
Rairi-san?!
She's looking for something!
I-Is it this?!
That was scary!
Is your outfit okay, Kuro-taso?
Um, yeah.
Sheesh, that scared me!
Rairi-san, what just...
Let's go!
Rairi-san's been in the bathroom a while.
R-Rairi-san... that's you, right?
Freaky, huh?
She talked!
Um... well...
I figured you were someone
I could open up to.
Will you listen to my story?
People teased me for a long
time, calling me Gori-Rairi.
It was hard, but since
I was such a positive person,
I played into it and laughed it off.
Then in my third year of middle school,
a guy I fell hard for loved my jokes.
The next thing I knew,
we were like a comedy duo.
For the first time,
I was glad to be such a gorilla.
I was so happy to be with him, I started
playing up my gorilla stuff hard.
Ook, ook, ook!
I don't have this much fun
with anyone else, Rairi.
H-Hey, don't say that. I'm gonna
seriously fall for you, Okada.
Sure. Fall as hard as you like.
He had a girlfriend, though.
Gori-Rairi, huh?
I think she likes you, Yu-kun.
Nah, I'm not into gorillas.
Rairi seems pretty down lately.
You're no fun, Rairi. Give us the usual!
Here. Your favorite food.
If you wanna play with
a gorilla that badly, let's do it!
I hate you!
All the unsympathetic idiots!
All the men who lead people on
despite having girlfriends!
The world that doesn't care
about ugly people!
This face of mine!
My whole self!
I hate it all!
Thankfully, I fell into the bushes by the road
and just needed a month in the hospital.
The kids from my class came to see me and
apologize, but my heart remained frozen.
I figured they were still just laughing.
But most of all, I hated myself.
Anyway, that was when I found this.
It came with a magazine.
A collab with a famous actress.
You can't fix a gorilla.
Hey, Raimu-chan.
You look kinda different today.
Is it the makeup?
You look so pretty!
Pretty? Me?
I'd been looking for something
to pull me out of the darkness.
Makeup gave me awful breakouts
for the longest time,
and when no one complimented
me, it made me nervous.
I was on the verge of
giving up so many times...
But each time I told myself, "It's okay!
I'm super pretty! Posi-peace!"
I looked in the mirror
and complimented myself!
But it was only recently that
I really started liking myself.
Wow. It must have taken
so much effort to learn all of that!
But even now, I only show my
real face to people I really trust.
Don't tell the people at school
about the gorilla stuff, 'kay?
Right!
I've got a dream, too.
I'd like to launch my own makeup brand.
I want to create makeup that allows girls,
with no confidence, like us,
to make a change if they want it.
That's why I work hard on my
cosmetics reports every day!
So I can get more work!
I know you can do it, Rairi-san!
Invent some makeup that
can make even a kaiju cute!
Kaiju?
Oh, nothing.
I mean, make cosmetics
good enough to do that!
Yeah, I will!
I'll make gorillas and kaiju
and everyone pretty!
Rairi-san was so strong.
I guess there's a reason
people like her are so amazing.
I'd better work hard, too.
I'm home!
Welcome home, Kuro-ta—
What happened to your face?
Are you wearing makeup?!
Is it that surprising?!
And not you too, Jumbo King!
I don't think it suits you, Kuro-tan.
I like you best
when you look like yourself.
Well, I get to decide how
I like myself best!
Except you're doing it
for Minami-kun, right?
Maybe it really doesn't suit me?
But Rairi-san knows what she's doing...
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
Ready for the field trip
in two days? I can't wait
to get to Okutama!
Ready for the field trip?
I can't wait to get to Okutama!
The field trip, huh?
I hope we can spend
our free time together.
Maybe I'll take the lipstick.
I'm pretty sure he liked it...
Kuro-tan, dinner—
Why are you shouting?!
You'll wake up the neighbors!
Knock first!
Next week's sweet treat is...
Marshmallows!
Plain or toasted, they're delicious!